Here's something that the exam now asks you,
which is about AWS Local Zones.
So the idea is that we have these availabilities zones
and these regions all around the world,
but now there's the concept of local zones,
which allows you to place compute storage database
and other services that are selected by database
closer to end users,
to run latency sensitive applications.
So the idea is that you will extend your AWS region
to one or more locations, one or more
quote-unquote availability zones,
one or more. Then they're called,
they're actually called local zones.
So this is compatible with EC2, RDS,
ECS, EBS, ElastiCache, Direct Connect and so on.
And so here's an example,
and we'll see this in the hands on very quickly.
So there's a region Northern Virginia, US-East-1,
and has six AZ by default,
but you can extend these AZs with more local zones.
So we have Boston Chicago, Dallas, Houston,
Miami, and so on.
So how does that work? Well, here's your region,
US-east-1 with two AZs,
but it's possible for you to define a local zone in Boston
and then extend your VPC
to be going across these AZs and local zones.
And then you would be able to launch an EC2 instance
into this local zone.
Now that may be confusing, So let's go into the console
to see how that works.
So I am in the EC2 console
and let me first pick a region
that does not have local zone.
For example, let me pick, let me pick Europe, Ireland.
So I'm going to pick Europe, Ireland and then under settings
right here, there is zones.
So I'm going to click on zones, as you can see,
in Ireland, we have three AZs right here.
They're enabled by default, and this is it.
There's no local zone, nothing else, right?
But if I switch to US-East-1 for Northern Virginia,
as we can see now we have a lot of options.
We have local zones, and then if I scroll down,
we have wavelength zones,
and then we have the availability zones.
So we have six AZ in US-East-1.
Okay? So there are enabled by default,
but our focus right now is local zones.
We can enable a local zone, for example,
if we knew that we had users in Boston and we really,
really want them to have low-latency access to our
applications directly from Boston,
then we can enable the local zone in Boston.
So I will manage this
and then I will enable this local zone
and update the zone group. And then I will say, yes, enable.
So now Boston is actually going to be enabled.
So let me just wait for it to take effect.
So I just refresh, and as you can see now,
the US East Boston, so US-East-1-Boston-1, is enabled.
And so what that means is that if I go into my instances
and launch an instance, choose Amazon Linux 2,
and then T2 micro, just to show you.
Then in the instance details, in terms of network,
we have our VPC, editors of subnets,
We still have our six subnets,
but it's possible for us to create a new subnet.
And this is quite advanced so,
you don't have to follow along with me if you don't
understand what I'm doing, but we choose the subnets.
We'll call it Boston subnets.
And for the AZ, I can actually choose
my US-East-1-Boston-1 subnets.
And now for the CIDR blocks.
So don't worry if you don't understand,
this is really advanced,
and this is not going to be asked at the exams.
I will choose 172.31.96.0/20.
Don't ask me why.
this is more advanced than the networking bits of AWS.
But I just want to show you that we can create a subnet and
associate it with a local zone.
Okay, so we are creating a subnet.
It's successful. Now back into my launch wizard.
I can just refer to the PC
and then here I have the option
to choose my bus and subnets.
So that's it really, I will not go ahead
with creating these two instance,
but at least you saw that it is possible
for us to extend our VPC to local zones,
and therefore deploy EC2 instances closer to our users.
That's it for this lecture.
I hope you understand now what local zones are,
and I will see you in the next lecture.